<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Discover Romania</string>
    <string name="category_cities">Cities</string>
    <string name="category_villages">Villages</string>
    <string name="category_castles">Castles</string>
    <string name="category_mountains">Mountains</string>
    <string name="category_unesco_sites">Unesco Sites</string>
    <string name="category_monasteries">Monasteries</string>
    <string name="bucharest">Bucharest</string>
    <string name="bucharest_description">Known for its wide, tree-lined boulevards, glorious Belle Époque buildings and a reputation for the high life (which in the 1900s earned its nickname of \"Little Paris\"), Bucharest, Romania\'s largest city and capital, is today a bustling metropolis and the cultural, industrial and financial centre of Romania.</string>
    <string name="cluj_napoca">Cluj-Napoca</string>
    <string name="cluj_napoca_description">With one of the most vibrant economies in the country and a population of around 330,000, Cluj is today a vibrant cultural and educational city. The six state and several private universities located here also make Cluj Napoca the city with the largest percentage of student population in Romania.</string>
    <string name="timisoara">Timisoara</string>
    <string name="timisoara_description">The first record of the city of Timisoara, built on the site of an ancient Roman fortress called Castrum Regium. \nThemes, dates back to 1212. Over the years, Timisoara, the largest city in western Romania, has been influenced by many cultures. The charm of this city, settled on the northern bank of the Bega River, lies in its distinct architectural character and vibrant cultural life.</string>
    <string name="iasi">Iasi</string>
    <string name="iasi_description">Iasi is the most important political, economic and cultural centre of the province of Moldavia as well as one of the oldest cities in Romania. The city prides itself with publishing the first Romanian newspaper and establishing the first Romanian university. Over the past 500 years, history, culture and religious life have molded the city\'s unique character.</string>
    <string name="constanta">Constanta</string>
    <string name="constanta_description">Situated at the crossroads of several commercial routes, Constanta lies on the western coast of the Black Sea, 185 miles from the Bosphorus Strait. An ancient metropolis and Romania\'s largest sea port, Constanta traces its history some 2,500 years. Its historical monuments, ancient ruins, grand Casino, museums and shops, and proximity to beach resorts make it the focal point of Black Sea coast tourism.</string>
    <string name="brasov">Brasov</string>
    <string name="brasov_description">Fringed by the peaks of the Southern Carpathian Mountains and resplendent with gothic, baroque and renaissance architecture, as well as a wealth of historical attractions, Brasov is one of the most visited places in Romania. \nBrasov is home to one of the the narrowest streets in Europe. The Rope Street is approximately four feet wide and it links Cerbului Street with Poarta Schei Street.</string>
    <string name="sibiu">Sibiu</string>
    <string name="sibiu_description">Sibiu (Hermannstadt in German) was the largest and wealthiest of the seven walled citadels built in the 12th century by German settlers known as Transylvanian Saxons. Sibiu\'s Old Town retains the grandeur of its earlier days when rich and powerful guilds dominated regional trade. In 1797, Samuel von Hahnemann opened in Sibiu the world\'s first homeopathic laboratory. The first book in the Romanian language was printed in Sibiu in 1544.</string>
    <string name="targu_mures">Targu Mures</string>
    <string name="targu_mures_description">Named literally for a \”market\” on the Mures River and known as the city of roses, Targu Mures (Marosvásárhely in Hun¬garian ~ Neumarkt am Mieresch in German) enjoys the best of both Romanian and Hungarian cultures. Numerous vestiges attest the presence of Neolithic cultures and those of the Bronze and Metal Ages in this area. Archaeological diggings have brought to light Roman relics in the surrounding towns.</string>
    <string name="alba_iulia">Alba-Iulia</string>
    <string name="alba_iulia_description">One of the oldest settlements in Romania, known in ancient time as Apulum, Alba Iulia served as the largest military and economic center during the Roman occupation. In the old town visitors can stroll along the wide, tree-lined streets of the Habsburg citadel, one of the most impressive in Europe, to discover the historical, cultural and architectural places of interest of Alba Iulia.</string>
    <string name="suceava">Suceava</string>
    <string name="suceava_description">Suceava is an excellent starting point for trips to the many historical, cultural and natural attractions travelers can enjoy in the Bucovina region. Suceava is also the gateway to visiting the Painted Monasteries of Bucovina.</string>
    <string name="sighisoara">Sighisoara</string>
    <string name="sighisoara_description">The origins of Sighisoara city go back to the Roman times. Sighisoara (Schäßburg - Schassburg or Schäsbrich in German) still stands as one of the most beautiful and best-preserved medieval towns in Europe. Designated as a World Heritage Site by UNESCO, this perfectly intact 16th century gem with nine towers, cobbled streets, burgher houses and ornate churches rivals the historic streets of Old Prague or Vienna for atmospheric magic.</string>
    <string name="targu_jiu">Targu Jiu</string>
    <string name="targu_jiu_description">A former Roman settlement, the city of Targu Jiu lies at the foothills of the Carpathian Mountains, on the banks of the river Jiu. Constantin Brancusi, one of the most influential modern sculptors of the 20th century, was born near Targu Jiu, in Hobita. Although he lived and worked for most of his life in Paris, his legacy is also preserved in Romania, in the city of Targu Jiu.</string>
    <string name="transylvania">Transylvania</string>
    <string name="transylvania_description">In Transylvania, you will find villages clustered around ancient Saxon citadels, edifices that often enclose exquisite churches built by German settlers from the 12th to the 16th centuries. A lovely half-hour drive south of the medieval city of Sibiu takes you into the pastoral landscapes of Marginimea Sibiului, one of Transylvania\'s best-preserved ethnographic areas.</string>
    <string name="apuseni_mountains_villages">Apuseni Mountains</string>
    <string name="apuseni_mountains_villages_description">Villages in the Apuseni Mountains are even more remote and lost in time. \nIf you wish to discover local life and preserved traditions, one of the main points of interest is the Aries Valley, where the beautiful villages of Albac, Garda, and Arieseni are located.</string>
    <string name="bucovina">Bucovina</string>
    <string name="bucovina_description">Some of Romania\'s most beautiful countryside is found in Bucovina, whose rolling green hills nestle villages and monasteries in their valleys. Horses, decked with red-tasseled bridles, travel country lanes, as villagers crows churchyards in traditional folk dress on Sundays and holidays. Bucovina remains the heart of craft mastery in Moldova.</string>
    <string name="maramures">Maramures</string>
    <string name="maramures_description">Maramures is an area of the country known for its timeless tranquility. Baia Mare is a good starting point for visiting some of the area\'s traditional villages: Iza, Viseu, Mara and Cosau.  Unique to this region are the local village churches, made of wood and dominated by magnificent Gothic spires. The Merry Cemetery of Sapanta is a 20-minute drive from Sighet. Here, colorful folk art pictures and witty words carved into wooden headstones immortalize the deceased\'s foibles, occupations or family problems.</string>
    <string name="castles_and_fortresses">Castles and Fortresses</string>
    <string name="bran_castle">Bran Castle</string>
    <string name="bran_castle_description">Surrounded by an aura of mystery and legend and perched high atop a 200-foot-high rock, Bran Castle owes its fame to its imposing towers and turrets. Narrow winding stairways lead through some 60 timbered rooms, many connected by underground passages, which house collections of furniture, weapons and armor dating from the 14th to the 19th centuries.</string>
    <string name="corvin_castle">Corvin Castle</string>
    <string name="corvin_castle_description">The greatest Gothic-style castle in Romania, Corvin was built by the Anjoufamily on the site of a former Roman camp. The castle served as a fortress until the mid-14th century when it became the residence of Transylvania\'s ruler, Iancu de Hunedoara. Iancu upgraded the fortress transforming it into the most stunning castle in Transylvania. \nThe beautifully preserved structure features a sumptuous Knights\' Hall, an impressive drawbridge, high buttresses, inner courtyards, a chapel and some 50 rooms resplendent with medieval art.</string>
    <string name="fagaras_fortress">Fagaras Fortress</string>
    <string name="fagaras_fortress_description">Built in 1310 on the site of a former 12th century wooden fortress (burned by the Tartars in 1241), Fagaras was enlarged between the 15th and 17th centuries and was considered one of the strongest fortifications in Transylvania. \nThe fortress was surrounded by a deep moat which, in times of war or social unrest, could easily be filled with water from a nearby mountain brook. A bridge over the moat provided the only access point.</string>
    <string name="peles_castle">Peles Castle</string>
    <string name="peles_castle_description">Nestled at the foot of the Bucegi Mountains in the picturesque town of Sinaia, Peles Castle is a masterpiece of German new-Renaissance architecture, considered by many one of the most stunning castles in Europe. \nPeles Castle was the first European castle entirely lit by electrical current. The electricity was produced by the castle\'s own plant.</string>
    <string name="rasnov_fortress">Rasnov Fortress</string>
    <string name="rasnov_fortress_description">Rasnov Fortress (Rosenau in German), is located on a rocky hilltop in the Carpathian Mountains, 650 ft. above the town of Rasnov. First mentioned in an official document in 1331, the fortress was built by Teutonic Knights as protection against invading Tartars and was later enlarged by the local Saxon population. Recently, the old fortress has been restored to its former glory and today, you can visit the impressive remains.</string>
    <string name="viscri_fortified_church">Viscri Fortified Church</string>
    <string name="viscri_fortified_church_description">One of the most interesting Saxon fortified churches is located in the village of Viscri (Weisskirch in German). \nThe name comes from the German Weisse Khirche, meaning white church. Unlike other Transylvanian fortified churches, Viscri was built around 1100 by the Szekler population and taken over by Saxon colonists in 1185. This explains why this unique gothic church displays a plain straight ceiling rather than a traditional vaulted one.</string>
    <string name="biertan_fortified_church">Biertan Fortified Church</string>
    <string name="biertan_fortified_church_description">Surrounded by quaint streets and vineyards, the 15th century fortified church at Biertan is perched high on a hill in the middle of the village. Three tiers of 35-foot-high defensive walls, connected by towers and gates, encircled the complex, making the church impossible to conquer during medieval times. Featuring late-gothic architecture with heavy doors and double exterior walls, the church boasts the largest Transylvanian multi-paneled wooden altar and a remarkable wooden door which once protected the treasures in the sacristy.</string>
    <string name="harman_fortified_church">Harman Fortified Church</string>
    <string name="harman_fortified_church_description">Located in the heart of Harman (Honigburg in German, meaning Honey Castle) village, this fortified church dates back to the 13th century when Saxons built the original structure. Strong walls and bulwarks surrounded the church and on its sides, massive towers were added.The choir was built in a square shape with a vault resembling a cross. It was surrounded by two chapels, indicating the influence of the Cistercian style.</string>
    <string name="jidvei_bethlen_haller_castle">Jidvei Bethlen Haller Castle</string>
    <string name="jidvei_bethlen_haller_castle_description">The Bethlen Castle was built in the 16th century in the French Renaissance style and restored in the 17th and 18th centuries when Baroque elements were added. The Reformed Church, situated next to the Castle, is a 13th century structure. The Jidvei (Bethlen-Haller) castle, with its eclectic combination of architectural styles, is located on the outskirts of Cetatea de Balta and it ofers its guests with quaint views of the village.</string>
    <string name="prejmer_fortified_church">Prejmer Fortified Church</string>
    <string name="prejmer_fortified_church_description">The largest fortified church in southeastern Europe, Prejmer (Tartlau in German) was built by Teutonic knights in 1212-1213. The powerful surrounding walls are 40 feet high and 10-15 feet thick. Historical records attest that in its 500 years of existence, the fortress was besieged 50 times. However, it was only captured once, in 1611 by Gabriel Báthori, Prince of Transylvania.</string>
    <string name="saschiz_fortified_church">Saschiz Fortified Church</string>
    <string name="saschiz_fortified_church_description">Saschiz is renowned not only as home to one of Transylvania\'s finest fortified churches but also as a carpentry and wood-painting center. It was here that Saschiz blue pottery was born in 1702. The Evangelical Church of Saschiz was built between 1493 and 1496 by Saxon colonists. The monument is very impressive due to its sheer size and the way the fortifying elements have been adapted to the shape of a church building.</string>
    <string name="valea_viilor_fortified_church">Valea Viilor Fortified Church</string>
    <string name="valea_viilor_fortified_church_description">Located in the Vineyards Valley, this fortified church was built in 1263 in gothic style and was enlarged and fortified in the 15th and 16th centuries by adding a range of 26-foot-tall and five-foot- wide walls. A unique element is the well in the center of the church choir that provided water for the locals during sieges. Inside, you can admire Saxon furniture and decorations dating from the 16th century.</string>
    <string name="unesco_sites">Unesco Sites</string>
    <string name="horezu_monastery">The Monastery of Horezu</string>
    <string name="horezu_monastery_description">Founded in 1690 by Prince Constantine Brancoveanu, the monastery of Horezu is a masterpiece of the \“Brancovenesti\” style. Renown for the richness of its sculptural detail, the treatment of its religious compositions and its painted decorative works, the monastery houses precious collections of frescos and icons dating from the end of the 17th century and beginning of the 18th century.</string>
    <string name="medieval_fortified_churches_of_transylvania">The Medieval Fortified Churches of Transylvania</string>
    <string name="medieval_fortified_churches_of_transylvania_description">Transylvania is home to nearly two hundred villages with fortified churches built by the Saxons between the 13th and 15th centuries. Having to withstand constant invaders, the villages\' central areas, where the church was located most of the time, were fortified with defense walls, having the capacity to shelter a large number of people. Seven of the fortified churches have been designated by UNESCO as World Heritage Sites.</string>
    <string name="historic_centre_of_sighisoara">Historic Centre of Sighisoara</string>
    <string name="historic_centre_of_sighisoara_description">Founded by German craftsmen and merchants known as the Saxons of Transylvania, Sighisoara is a fine example of a small, fortified medieval town which played an important strategic and commercial role on the fringes of central Europe for several centuries. Sighisoara, one of the most beautiful towns in the heart of Transylvania, looks today much as it did 500 years ago.</string>
    <string name="painted_monasteries_of_bucovina">The painted Monasteries of Bucovina</string>
    <string name="painted_monasteries_of_bucovina_description">Among the most picturesque treasures of Romania are the Painted Churches of Bucovina (northeastern Romania). With their painted exterior walls, decorated with 15th and 16th century elaborate frescoes (featuring portraits of saints and prophets, scenes from the life of Jesus, images of angels and demons, heaven and hell), deemed as masterpieces of Byzantine art, these churches are one-of-a-kind architectural sites in Europe.</string>
    <string name="wooden_churches_of_maramures">The Wooden Churches of Maramures</string>
    <string name="wooden_churches_of_maramures_description">The Wooden Churches of Maramures are unique in shape and ornamentation and eight of them – in Barsana, Budesti Josani, Desesti, Ieud, Plopis, Poienile Izei, Rogoz and Surdesti, have been recognized by UNESCO as World Heritage Sites. The characteristic high roofs and tall, narrow, pointed steeples are often collectively described as the Gothic Style of Maramures.</string>
    <string name="dacian_fortress">Dacian Fortresses of the Orastie Mountains (Sarmizegetusa Regia)</string>
    <string name="dacian_fortress_description">Dating from the 1st centuries B.C. and A.D the Dacian fortresses in Orastie Mountains show an unusual fusion of military and religious architectural techniques and concepts from the classical world and the late European Iron Age.  Built as a defense ring around the capital of the Dacian kingdom, Sarmizegetusa (also Sarmisegetuza), the fortresses at Banita, Capalna, Costesti - Blidaru, Costesti – Cetatuie, Luncani - Piatra Rosie once formed the nucleus of the Dacian Kingdom.</string>
    <string name="apuseni_nature_park">APUSENI NATURE PARK</string>
    <string name="apuseni_nature_park_description">The Apuseni Nature Park (Parcul Natural Apuseni) - known as the cavers\' paradise, protects one of the most interesting cave fauna in the country. Limestone underlies most of the park and is responsible for the area\'s impressive landforms. Sculptured mountain ridges, mysterious underground rivers, and delicate cave decorations will surely keep visitors\' photo cameras busy.</string>
    <string name="bicazului_gorges">BICAZULUI GORGES - HĂȘMAȘ NATIONAL PARK</string>
    <string name="bicazului_gorges_description">The Bicaz Gorges are famous for their 1000 ft. limestone rocks towering over narrow roads and passes. The road that slices through the Bicaz Gorges is among Romania\'s most stunning and spectacular. For kayakers and fly-fishing enthusiasts the park\'s main attraction is the Red Lake, created in 1837 after a major natural landslide.</string>
    <string name="calimani_national_park">CĂLIMANI NATIONAL PARK</string>
    <string name="calimani_national_park_description">Mountain with volcanic origins, Calimani features the biggest inactive caldera in Europe (about 6 miles in diameter). Massive eruptive rocks and craters of old volcanoes in the Calimani National Park (Parcul National Calimani) are spawned over breathtaking landscapes, matched by the presence of large areas of natural ecosystems and the abundance of Swiss stone pine and juniper trees.</string>
    <string name="ceahlau_national_park">CEAHLĂU NATIONAL PARK</string>
    <string name="ceahlau_national_park_description">Surrounded by watercourses and dam lakes, Ceahlau Mountain, the Olympus of Romania, displays an incredible concentration of flora - over 2,000 flower species, and wildlife. Fossil limestone, the rock formations Dochia, Cusma Dorobantului, and the Duruitoarea waterfall are just some of the main attractions in the park.</string>
    <string name="piatra_craiului">PIATRA CRAIULUI NATIONAL PARK</string>
    <string name="piatra_craiului_description">Piatra Craiului Natural Park features the longest and highest limestone ridge in the country (over 15 miles long and 6560 ft. high). Bordered by glacial lakes, the ridge is regarded as one of the most beautiful sights in the Carpathians.  The traditional villages of Magura, Pestera, Ciocanu, Sirnea, make for interesting starting points for the routes on the eastern slope and for getting in touch with the traditional Romanian way of life.</string>
    <string name="retezat_national_park">RETEZAT NATIONAL PARK</string>
    <string name="retezat_national_park_description">Over one third of the Romanian flora can be found in the Retezat Mountains. High meadows create a haven for rare alpine flora. Long, steep slopes are covered with different types of forest, especially beech, spruce and fir. \nPeaks of differing heights, many topping the 8,028 ft. mark (such as Peleaga Peak), provide hikers with plenty of challenges. Travelers willing to tackle them will have their efforts well rewarded.</string>
    <string name="transfagarasan">TRANSFAGARASAN</string>
    <string name="transfagarasan_description">Also labeled \"the Road to the Sky\", \"the Road to the Clouds\", \"the Best Driving Road in the World\" and even \"A spectacular Monument to Earth-Moving Megalomania\", the TransFagarasan climbs, twists and descends right through Moldoveanu and Negoiu - the highest peaks in Fagaras Mountains and in Romania.</string>
    <string name="transalpina">TRANSALPINA</string>
    <string name="transalpina_description">If adventure and Alpine scenery sound alluring, the TransAlpina road offers an ideal mix of the two. Winding its way through valleys and plateaus up to 7,038 feet – a height not reached by any other mountain passage in Romania – the TransAlpina road offers breathtaking views together with lots of driving excitement.</string>
    <string name="transbucegi">TRANSBUCEGI</string>
    <string name="transbucegi_description">Sinaia is home of the stunning Peles castle but if, while in or near town, you will feel the need for higher elevation, even fresher air and sweeping landscapes you can soak in some of Romania\'s most breathtaking vistas without even leaving your car. Just take the TransBucegi road from Sinaia to the Bucegi Mountains Plateau.</string>
    <string name="arbore_monastery">Arbore Monastery</string>
    <string name="arbore_monastery_description">Perhaps a tour of Bucovina\'s Painted Monasteries should begin here. After all, the highlight of the small Arbore (Are\' bo ray) church is a scene from Genesis, which adorns the western wall. The only church in the region with no belfry towers, because it was not built by a prince, the monastery was founded in 1503 by Luca Arbore, the advisor of Stephen the Great.</string>
    <string name="humor_monastery">Humor Monastery</string>
    <string name="humor_monastery_description">The church, topped by a cross-shaped shingled roof, is without a steeple, indicating that it was built by a court official rather than a prince. The predominant hues of the frescoes are reddish brown with some rich blues and green infusions. An extremely valuable collection of icons from the 16th century is displayed in the monastery.</string>
    <string name="moldovita_monastery">Moldovita Monastery</string>
    <string name="moldovita_monastery_description">The Monastery of Moldovita (Mol do vee\' tsa), located in the village of Vatra Moldovitei, was built by Petru Rares in 1532. The predominantly gold and deep blue paintings on the exterior walls were completed in 1537. The large and vivid Siege of Constantinople highlights the frescoes. The Siege of Constantinople frescoes were inspired by a poem dedicated to the Virgin Mary in thanksgiving for her intervention in saving the city of Constantinople from a Persian attack in A.D. 626.</string>
    <string name="probota_monastery">Probota Monastery</string>
    <string name="probota_monastery_description">Only the church and the prince\'s residence remain today from the original ensemble founded by Petru Rares in 1530. In 1532, the church featured both outside and inside frescoes. In the 19th century, a large part of the mural paintings were replaced. Probota was the first monastery to have external frescoes painted in Moldavia. High walls surround Probota with corner towers for defense and a gate tower built in 1550.</string>
    <string name="sucevita_monastery">Sucevita Monastery</string>
    <string name="sucevita_monastery_description">High walls and heavily buttressed defensive towers surround the great monastic complex of Sucevita, giving it the appearance of a fortress. Founded in 1581 by Gheorghe Movila, Bishop of Radauti, it was later expanded by his brother, Ieremia, ruling prince of Moldavia, who added massive ramparts and turrets. An elegant steeple resting on a star-shaped base tops the church. Sucevita was the last of the 22 painted churches of Bucovina and has the largest number of painted images.</string>
    <string name="voronet_monastery">Voronet Monastery</string>
    <string name="voronet_monastery_description">Perhaps the most famous and stunning of the painted monasteries is Voronet (Vo ro nets), founded in 1487 by Stephen the Great to celebrate a victory over the Turks. Widely known throughout Europe as \"the Sistine Chapel of the East\" due to its interior and exterior wall paintings, this monastery offers an abundance of frescoes featuring an intense shade of blue commonly known as Voronet blue. The composition of the paint continues to remain a mystery even now, more than 500 years after the church was built.</string>
</resources>